<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Code Bouquet</title><description>Code Bouquet</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 17:47:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Deciding on a Database</title><description>&lt;p&gt;On the heels of a great talk by the CTO of NPM - Laurie Voss, my thesis project team at Makersquare needed a database. Thankfully, the talk and our studies have informed us well, and after some short deliberation, we decided to use PostgreSQL. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relational databases like PostgreSQL and MySQL (aka databases which use &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL"&gt;structured query language&lt;/a&gt;) use binary code to store information. This allows for speedy lookup times, in addition to efficient queries that can compare different, variable datasets. There are some limitations: namely, the structure of your dataset is most easily architechted and pliable at its initiation/at the outset. Additionally, entries are space-limited by a pre-defined integer/character specification and count. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An SQL database made most sense for our project because we wanted to be able to make comparative queries on the fly. Having a leaderboard that involved significant data queries/comparisons between users would have been difficult using a NoSQL object that consists of stored JSON objects, especially if we only wanted the top scorers, for instance. In an SQL set up, we can create quickly query the table that keeps track of the value of interest, rather than iterating through each user's JSON store in order to find the value of interest and compare going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonrelational databases/NoSQL like Firebase allow for a quick storing of data and quick lookup, only when not seeking to compare datasets / identify relationships between them. They store data in no particular order, but the manner by which data is structured (ie the parameters, etc.) may be iterated on as desired. Additionally, unlike relational databases, they are not restricted by a pre-defined integer/character specification and count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We considered other databases, all of which have their own unique set of advantages and disadvantages. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/so-many-databases-so-hard-to-choose/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">27c05cd5-d909-4f6e-a686-acc86485ffdb</guid><dc:creator>Sean Conroy</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 17:45:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Angular Binding Issues</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Angular has some issues - though probably not of the fundamental sort. They're not the kind of issues that might convince you to leave it in reckless abandon, though they might eat into your lunch hour (like they did to my own :o ).. unless, that is, you've encountered the following issue and you're reading this blog! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day I was building a view in an application that required a user interface with form validation: I wanted to allow users to submit information, but only particular information (the right information, character limits, etc.) accompanied by an image. Angular makes it super simple to carry out form validation. After reviewing a mighty &lt;a href="https://scotch.io/tutorials/angularjs-form-validation"&gt;tutorial on scotch.io&lt;/a&gt;, I took to my text editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the form, two-way data binding worked great on all of the text inputs/textarea, but not so well on the file input - where images were to be attached for uploading. A cursory search revealed that others had the &lt;a href="https://github.com/angular/angular.js/issues/1375"&gt;same&lt;/a&gt; issue. I tried a &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/16207202/required-attribute-not-working-with-file-input-in-angular-js"&gt;directive&lt;/a&gt; that would detect when a file was uploaded and therefore validate the form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;app.directive('validFile', function () {
  return {
    require: 'ngModel',
    link: function (scope, el, attrs, ngModel) {
      ngModel.$render = function () {
        ngModel.$setViewValue(el.val());
      };
      el.bind('change', function () {
        scope.$apply(function () {
          ngModel.$render();
        });
      });
    }
  };
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...but the same directive did not actually succeed in uploading that file: The back-end's attempt to parse the post request's data returned evidence of the void: cannot read ~ of undefined. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My solution was to patch in a bit of jQuery, which worked swimmingly. In the controller, we created a new FormData object and appended the necessary information to it, substituting a jQuery selector for the item that we couldn't bind via angular:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
fd.append('file', $('.image')[0].files[0], 'image');
fd.append('dish_name', $scope.dishname);
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allowed us to both validate the form using the above directive and ensure that it was being appended to the FormData.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Upload Image:&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;input type="file" name="image" class="image" ng-model="file" valid-file required accept="image/*"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/input&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;{{ reviewForm.image.$error.required &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ' - please upload an image file - ' || 'Looks good!'}}&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Dish Name:&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;textarea class="review-dishname" name="dishname" ng-model="dishname" ng-minlength="2" ng-required="true"&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/textarea&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p ng-show="reviewForm.dishname.$error.required &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !reviewForm.dishname.$pristine" class="help-block"&amp;gt;Please enter the name of the dish you're reviewing.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angular leverages jQuery to meet different ends, and I'm not sure why it doesn't do so in this instance. But I'm sure that it will be a likely new feature/patch come Angular 2.0 - due any month now. It makes perfect sense that the ng-model service should work for 'input type=file' and therefore permit two-way data binding, so that users can upload content seamlessly, and, for example, be made aware in real-time that their content has been uploaded. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sean&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/angular-sometimes-doesnt-bind-well/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">e60f7b0a-f0f0-4d90-a75b-f7b42875102c</guid><dc:creator>Sean Conroy</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 06:22:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Welcome! I'm Hosting with Ghost on GitHub Pages!!</title><description>&lt;h3 id="helloworld"&gt;Hello, world!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id="cmovalacosita"&gt;¿Cómo va la cosita?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You're very welcome to join me as I blog about software and the world around me. I hope you'll find this material interesting, helpful, or perhaps insightful. I will try to the best of my ability to give credit where credit is due. For starters, this site is in part made possible by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://ghost.org/"&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; Blogging Platform - a super simple, minimal text editor that can be  hosted on GitHub Pages. I leveraged &lt;a href="https://github.com/axitkhurana/buster"&gt;Buster&lt;/a&gt; to create a static instance of Ghost, which I run locally to edit my page. This &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/23375422/how-to-setup-github-pages-to-redirect-dns-requests-from-subdomain-e-g-www-to"&gt;Stack Overflow post&lt;/a&gt; gave me the resources to iron out my redirecting woes in no time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have or develop questions while reading my posts, simply reach out to me - I really do appreciate every bit of feedback. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sean&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/welcome-to-ghost/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60811cb7-baeb-4312-9fbc-8aa8d6932de3</guid><dc:creator>Sean Conroy</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 03:35:48 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>